Guide to the Charles Stacy French Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles Stacy French papers
1935-1989
SC0474
French, Charles Stacy, 1907-
35 Linear feet
Papers include correspondence, articles, speeches, manuscripts, lab notes, charts, and computer printouts pertaining largely to his research interests in the photosynthesis of purple bacteria, spectroscopy of plant pigments, and the construction of spectroscopic equipment. Papers also include approximately 400 glass and film slides of charts, graphs, plants, equipment, laboratories, and other scientists.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of C.S. French, 1994.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
French, plant physiologist, was director of the Dept. of Plant Biology of the Carnegie Institution, located on the Stanford University campus, from 1947 until his retirement in 1973. Prior to his arrival at Carnegie, he taught at the Harvard Medical School, the University of Chicago, and the University of Minnesota.
Description of the Collection
Papers include correspondence, articles, speeches, manuscripts, lab notes, charts, and computer printouts pertaining largely to his research interests in the photosynthesis of purple bacteria, spectroscopy of plant pigments, and the construction of spectroscopic equipment. Papers also include approximately 400 glass and film slides of charts, graphs, plants, equipment, laboratories, and other scientists.
Access Terms
Amesz, Jan.; Briggs, Winslow R.; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974.; Duysens, L. N. M.; Ebert, James D. (James David), 1921-2001; Fork, David Charles.; Franck, James, 1882-1964.; French, Charles Stacy, 1907-; Goedheer, Joop C.; Halldal, Per.; Haskins, Caryl P. (Caryl Parker), 1908-2001; Hastings, A. Baird (Albert Baird), 1895-1987.; Hill, Robert, SC.D.; Lang, Anton.; Latimer, Paul Henry.; Mcleod, Guy C.; Myers, Jack Edgar, 1913-; Nielsen, Niels Christian.; Schiff, Jerome A.; Shibata, Kazuo, 1918-; Smith, James H. C.; Tamiya, Hiroshi, 1903-1984.; Tang, Pei-sung, 1903-; Thomas, J. B. (Jan Bartholomeus), 1907-; Vidaver, William E.; Virgin, Hemming I.; Botany.; Laboratory notes.; Photosynthesis.; Plant physiology.; Plant pigments.; Slides.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence, 1973 - 1989 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1971; French’s lab books, 1947-1974; bibliography and biography file; biography of Jens Christian Clausen by C.S. French (Box 2)
  - Lab notes, articles, papers; many concern the curve analyzer and other apparatus (Box 3)
  - Lab notes; talks, 1937-1947; Chicago work; subjects include curve analyzer, differential spectrophotometer, and photosynthesis (Box 4)
  - Lab notes and papers re purple bacteria and photosynthesis (Box 5)
  - Rolled Charts (Box 6)
  - Computer Printouts (Box 7)
  - Computer Printouts; Data & MSS figures for publication (Box 8)
  - Computer Printouts (Box 9)
  - Absorption Spectra: Computer Printouts & Lab Notes (Box 10)
  - Absorption Spectra: Computer Printouts & Lab Notes (Box 11)
  - Absorption Spectra, cont.; French's lab books, 1969-1980; computer printouts (Box 12)
  - Lab books; Lab notes, papers, correspondence, page proofs, typescript articles, 1955-1962 (Box 13)
  - Lab notes, papers, manuscripts, typescripts (Box 14)
  - Lab notes, typescript articles, reprints on fluorescence and other topics; speeches from the 1970s (Box 15)
  - Speeches, 1950s-1970s; correspondence 1936 - 1946; manuscripts (Box 16)
  - Lab notes, manuscripts, data for papers, mostly from 1940s (Box 17)
  - Lab notes on computer worksheets (Box 18)
  - Rolled charts and folders; computer tape (Box 19)
  - Computer printouts (Box 20)
  - Computer printouts: DSPEC, SPLOT, SCALE (Box 21)
  - Computer Printouts: BAND 1, BKG2, Basic Course, PROPS (1970), STAT, Digitizer, SYNSP, Splot & Resolv, Resolv & Splot Nielsen Manuscript (Box 22)
  - Computer Printouts, Graphs, Lab analysis (Box 23)
  - Glass Slides
    - Lab photos and miscellaneous photosynthesis (Box 24)
    - Photosynthesis pigments misc. (Box 24)
    - [unlabeled] (Box 24)
    - Chloroplast activity (Box 24)
    - Chloralla resp., purple bacteria (Box 25)
    - Misc. apparatus [and charts] (Box 25)
    - Curve analyzer (Box 25)
    - Fluorescence apparatus (Box 25)
    - Fluorescence apparatus (Box 26)
    - Fluorescence spectra (Box 26)
    - Derivative spectrophotometer (Box 26)
    - Forms of chlorophyll O (Box 27)
    - Chlorophyll formation (Box 27)
    - Chlorophyll formation (Box 28)
    - Misc. photosynthesis (Box 28)
    - Polarograph (Box 28)
    - Action spectra (Box 29)
    - Photosynthesis and miscellaneous (Box 29)
    - Oxygen concentration/chlorella/photosynthesis (Box 29)
    - Photosynthesis (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, individually labeled (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous glass slides, individually labeled (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous glass slides, individually labeled (Box 32)
    - 35mm film slides of charts, tables, graphs (Box 33)
    - 35mm film slides of plants, bacteria, labs and instruments, and people (Box 34)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1996-056
  - Grating tests and monochromotor const. fluoresc. spectrophotometer. C. S. French, 1974 -March 14, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - Action spectra for Chyll-formation; start of curve analyser; recording fluorescence spectrophotometer 1949-1952; monochromator calibrations. C. S. French (Box 1, Folder 192)
  - Fluorescence spectrophotometry. C. S. French, Jan. 1, 1953 -Dec. 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 214)
  - Automatic plotting of action spectra for photosynthesis. Porphyridium cruentum etc. Transients, various algae. C. S. French, Guy McLeod, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 259)
  - Fluorescence apparatus; claes chlorella fl. etc.; monochromator C. S. French, M. Lawrence, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 299)
  - Spectrophotometer. C. S. French, M. Lawrence, August 1966 -September 1975 (Box 2, Folder 316)
  - Action spectra. Glenn Ford and Hagar, Sept. 6, 1972 -March 1973 (Box 2, Folder 375)
  - Action and [illegible], 1987; includes copy of a letter to French from Jack Myers, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 399)
Index of Correspondents
Abelson, Philip Hauge 1 1975-
Ackerman, Edward A. 2 1961-67
Akoyunoglou, George 1 1980
Akoyunoglou, George 1 1980
Amero, R. C. 2 Letters 1945-
Amesz, Jan 1 1985
Anderson, A. A. 2 Letters 1945-
Anson, M. L. 2 Letters 1945-
Applegate, C. E. 2 Letters 1945-
Aronoff, Samuel 2 Letters 1945-
Astin, Allen V. 1 1975-
Avron, Mordhay Ed 1 1978
Badger. Murray 1 1978
Barghoorn, Elso S. 1 1977
Barker, Horace Albert 1 1985
Barker, Horace Albert 2 Letters 1945-
Barker, Joseph W. 2 Letters 1945-
Batra, Amla 1 1980
Bauer, G. Philip 2 1961-67
Bearden, Alan J. 1 1977
Bearden, Alan J. 1 1973-74
Behnke, John A. 1 1975-
Behnke, John A. 1 1980
Beier, W. 1 1977
BŽlanŽ, Szaj‡ni 1 1980
Bennett, Thomas Peter 1 1975-
Bethge, Heinz 1 1978
Bia lek-Bylka, G. E. 1 1986
Biddulph, Orlin 2 1970-71
Bj™rn, Lars Olof 1 1973-74
Bjšrn, Lars Olof 1 1983
Bjšrn, Lars Olof 1 1985
Black, Clanton C. 1 1978-79
Blegen, Theodore C. 2 Letters 1945-
Boardman, N. Keith 1 1973-74
Boardman, N. Keith 1 1977
Boardman, N. Keith 1 1987
Bolken 1 1973-74
Bonner, James 1 1975-
Borisov, Alexander Yu. 1 1984
Bouman, M. A. 1 1984
Boyd, George H. 2 Letters 1945-
Boynton, John E. 2 1970-71
Branscomb, Lewis M. 1 1980
Brenden, Francis 2 Letters 1945-
Briggs, Winslow R. 1 1975-
Briggs, Winslow R. 1 1979
Briggs, Winslow R. 1 1981
Briggs, Winslow R. 1 1984
Briggs, Winslow R. 1 1985
Britz, Steve J. 1 1978
Britz, Steve J. 1 1979
Brown, A. Peter 1 1977
Brown, Ray, E. 2 Letters 1945-
Bryan, Gary W. 1 1978
Bush, Vannevar 2 1935-1950
Calvin, Melvin 1 1976
Campbell, Angus 1 1978
Carmichael, Leonard 2 Letters 1945-
Chambers, Ann 1 1979
Chambers, Frank 1 1979
Cilento, Giuseppe 1 1977
Clayton, Roderick Keener 1 1975-
Clayton, Roderick Keener 1 1975-
Cleland, C. F. 1 1986
Clemens, Cyril 2 1970-71
Coates, Joseph F. 1 1978
Coberly, Barbara A. 1 1973-74
Coberly, Barbara A. 1 1975-
Coffey, W. C. 2 Letters 1945-
Coohill, Thomas 1 1981
Craig, Franr 2 Letters 1945-
Crawford, Bryce Jr. 1 1982
Crawford, Victoria B. 1 1975-
Crim, Dale 1 1980
Crofts, A. R. & Holmes, N. G. 1 1975-
Daly, J. M. 1 1984
Decker, John 2 1970-71
Decker, John 2 1961-67
Decoux 2 Letters 1945-
Dehaan, Robert L. 1 1987
Deluca, H. F. 1 1975-
Denis, M. 2 1968-69
Dick, John H. 1 1981
Doherty, Josephine K. 1 1981
Dowben, Robert M. 2 1970-71
Duda, George D. 1 1975-
Dugger, Mack 2 1970-71
Duke, Stan 1 1975-
Dunlap, Chesley M. 1 1979
Duysens, Lou 1 1986
Duysens, Lou 1 1987
Duysens, Lou. N. M. 1 1977
Ebersold, W. T. 1 1973-74
Ebert, James D. 1 1979
Ebert, James D. 1 1984
Ebert, James D. 1 1980
Edmondson, Yvette H. 1 1976
Edsall, John Tileston 2 Letters 1945-
Edsall, John Tileston 1 1979
Ehrman, Libert 1 1975-
Einhorn, Nathan R. 1 1973-74
Eisenstark, A. 1 1973-74
Emerson, Ralph 1 1977
Enloe, Alton J. 1 1979
Epel, David 1 1987
Epstein, Emanuel 1 1978
Fell, Antony F. 1 1983
Fork, David Charles 2 1961-67
Fork, David Charles 2 1951-60
Fork, David Charles 2 1968-69
Forster, Jackson W. 2 Letters 1945-
Franck, James 2 Letters 1945-
Freeman, Andrew R. 1 1975-
Frenkel, Albert W. 1 1982
FulleyLove, James 1 1973-74
Galston, Arthur W. 1 1984
Gingras, G. 2 1970-71
Ginkel, Gijs van 1 1984
Goedheer, Joop C. 1 1977
Golding, N. S. 2 Letters 1945-
Good, Morman 1 1979
Govindjee, M. 1 1981
Govindjee, M. 1 1982
Govindjee, M. 1 1984
Graham, JoRuth 1 1973-74
Greene, T. G. 1 1978
Greppin H. 1 1984
Gressley, Gene M. 1 1973-74
Grinwade, A. M. 1 1975-
Grundmann, Alan 1 1973-74
Hackerman, Norman 1 1979
Hagar, William 1 1975-
Hagar, William 1 1982
Hagar, William 1 1985
Hagen, Joel B. 1 1981
Hager, William 1 1983
Haines, D. E. 2 Letters 1945-
Hall, Eric. J. 1 1980
Halldal, Per 2 1970-71
Halldal, Per 2 1968-69
Halldal, Per 1 1973-74
Halldal, Per 1 1977
Hamilton, Robert L. 1 1980
Hamilton, Robert L. 1 1982
Hanson, J. B. 1 1985
Hardy, Arthur C. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Harms, Doreathea Siefermann 1 1982
Harte, Robert A. 2 1961-67
Harte, Robert A. 1 1973-74
Hartmann, Karl M. 1 1976
Haskins, Caryl P. 1 1979
Haskins, Caryl P. 2 1968-69
Hast, Adele 1 1982
Hastings, A. Baird 2 Letters 1945-
Haxo, Francis 1 1986
Heber, U. 1 1973-74
Heiss, Louis 1 1973-74
Heller, Craig 1 1984
Heller, W. 2 Letters 1945-
Henard, Kenneth R. 2 1968-69
Hesse, G. W. 2 Letters 1945-
Hiesey, William McKinley 1 1977
Hiesey, William McKinley 1 1982
Hiesey, William McKinley 1 1987
Hiesey, William McKinley 1 1976
Hiesry, William McKinley 1 1985
Hill, Robert 2 1970-71
Hill, Robert 1 1975-
Hill, Robert 1 1977
Hill, Robert 1 1978
Hill, Robert 1 1979
Hill, Robert 1 1982
Hiller, R. G. 1 1980
Hiyama, Tets 1 1979
Hoag, Donald G. 2 Letters 1945-
Hockett, Robert C. 2 Letters 1945-
Holton, Raymond, W. & Norris, Fred H. 1 1973-74
Holzer, Helmut 1 1977
Horecker, Bernard L. 1 1982
Humphreys, Adolph H. 2 Letters 1945-
Inoue, Yorinao 1 1976
Inoue, Yorinao 1 1983
Irving, Laurence 1 1973-74
Jacklet, Jon W. 1 1975-
Jackson, Peter G. C 1 1977
Jackson, Peter G. C. 1 1976
Johnson, Walter J. 2 Letters 1945-
Jones, Donald F. 2 1961-67
Jutila, John W. 1 1977
Kazuo, Shibata 1 1978
Klein, Norman 1 1975-
Klein, William 1 1981
Kramer, Paul J. 2 Letters 1945-
Krasnovsky, A. A. 1 1980
Krikorian, A. D. 2 1970-71
Kung, Shain-dou 1 1978-79 (Tang corresp.)
Kushida, Hiroshi 1 1979
Kylin, Anders 1 1982
Laird, W. David 1 1973-74
Lamborn, Ody H. 2 Letters 1945-
Lang, Anton 2 1970-71
Lang, Anton 1 1979
Lang, Anton 1 1985
Lapedes, Daniel N. 1 1978
Larson, Burneice M. 2 Letters 1945-
Latham, David J. 1 1978
Latimer, Paul Henry 1 1983
Latimer, Paul Henry 1 1984
Lawrence, D. B. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Leech 1 1980
Leonard, N. J. 1 1980
Levitt, J. 2 1968-69
Lewis, Charlton M. 2 1961-67
Lewis, Howard B. 2 Letters 1945-
Li, Teh-Ning 1 1981
Libby, Leona Marshall 1 1973-74
Lipke, Herbert 1 1973-74
Lipke, Herbert 1 1977
Little, John E. 2 Letters 1945-
Livingstion, Robert 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Loach, Paul Alan 1 1977
Loach, Paul Alan 1 1979
Loomis, W. E. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Luck, J. Murray 2 Letters 1945-
Luppert, John H. 1 1984
Luppert, John H. 1 1987
Luppert, John H. 1 1987
Macdowell, Hargur 1 1984
Machelis, Leonard 2 Machelis Letters 1945
Machelis, Leonard 2 Letters 1945-
Mailey, R. D. 2 Letters 1945-
Malakoff, Miriam T. 2 Letters 1945-
Mannan, R. Mannar 1 1982
Manning, Kenneth R. 1 1977
Markwell, John P. 1 1980
Matson, L. 2 Letters 1945-
McCay, Elizabeth 2 Letters 1945-
McGinnies, William Grovenor 1 1973-74
McGinnies, William Grovenor 1 1981
Mclean, L. V. 2 Letters 1945-
Mcleod, Guy 2 1961-67
Meader, R. G 2 Letters 1945-
Mehl, John 1 1973-74
Meister, A. 1 1978
Metzner, Helga 1 1973-74
Metzner, David E. 1 1975-
Metzner, Helga 1 1978
Metzner, Helga 1 1979
Metzner, Helga 1 1982
Metzner, Helga 1 1983
Metzner, Helga 1 1984
Metzner, Helga 1 1987
Miller, Oscar L. Jr. 1 1976
Miyachi, Shigetoh 1 1984
Mohr, John L. 1 1978
Moore, John, W. 2 Letters 1945-
Moore, Thomas 1 1973-74
Moran, Rami 1 1984
Morrey, Charles B. 2 1970-71
Mortimer, Robert K. 1 1975-
Morton, J. K. 2 1970-71
Morton, R. A. 1 1973-74
Mothes, K. 1 1977
Moyse, A. 2 1961-67
Moyse, A. 1 1973-74
Mulkey, Timothy 1 1979
Murata, Norio 1 1975-
Murata, Norio 1 1976
Murray, Doug 1 1978-79 (Tang corresp.)
Myers, Jack Edgar 1 1980
Myers, Jack Edgar 1 1987
NŠf, Ulrich 1 1975-
Naylor, Aubrey W. 1 1976
Newman, David W. 1 1984
Newmark, Nathan M. 1 1976
Nichiporovich, A. A. 1 1975-
Nichiporovich, A. A. 1 1987
Nicholson, Frank 1 1981
Nielsen, Niels Christian 1 1975-
Nielsen, Niels Christian 1 1976
Nielsen, Niels Christian 1 1977
Nielsen, Niels Christian 1 1978
Nilan, Roxasnne 1 1985
Odum, Howard T. 1 1982
Olson, John Melvin 1 1976
Olson, John Melvin 1 1987
…quist, Gunnar 1 1973-74
…quist, Gunnar 1 1975-
Osnitskaya, Ludmilla 1 1975-
Pak, Simon J. 1 1973-74
Parker, Marion W. 2 1935-1950
Pauly, Philip J. 1 1986
Pauly, Philip J. 1 1987
Paxton, Cady 1 1973-74
Pearlstein, Robert M. 1 1978
Peckham, Robert F. 1 1976
Pedersen, P. O 1 1984
Pestell, W. A. 2 1935-1950
Pestell, W. A. 2 1951-60
Phelps, Ethel L. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Pietro, A. San 1 1975-
Pitzer, Kenneth S. 1 1976
Platko, Beatrice L. 2 1970-71
Poff, Ken 1 1977
Poteet, John W. Jr. 2 Letters 1945-
Powell, Jeffery R. 1 1975-
Prance, Ghillean T. 1 1978
Preer, John R. Jr. 1 1977
Press, Frank 1 1979
Press, Frank 1 1983
Press, Frank 1 1984
Prezelin, Barbara B. 1 1980
Price, C. A. 2 1961-67
Pursell, Edward M. 1 1985
Quinn, Jarus W. 1 1973-74
Quinn, Jarus, W. 1 1981
Raven, Peter H. 1 1982
Rawal, Bharat S. 1 1977
Raymond, Lawrence P. 1 1983
Raymond, Lawrence P. 1 1986
Raymond, Lawrence P. 1 1987
Riker, A. J. 2 1961-67
Ritchie, Gillian A. 1 1979
Ritchings, R. H. 2 1968-69
Robbins, J. 2 Letters 1945-
Roff, W. J. 2 1970-71
Rohatgi, K. K. 2 1970-71
Rosenbaum, Robert A. 2 1961-67
Rosenblith, Walter A. 1 1985
Rubin, Andrew B. 1 1975-
Ruby, R. H. 1 1979
RŸdiger, W. 2 1968-69
Ryssov-Nielsen, Henning 1 1975-
Sackett, Ross D. 2 1968-69
Safwat, Fuad 1 1979
Salisbury, Frank B. 1 1984
Salisbury, Frank B. 1 1987
Schaefer, John P. 1 1981
Schiff, Jerome A. 2 1961-67
Schiff, Jerome A. 1 1979
Schrohe, B. N. 1 1973-74
Sestak, Zdenek 1 1987
Sestak, Zdenek 1 1981
Sheridan, Harold 1 1981
Sherman, Elizabeth J. 1 1987
Sherman, Louis 1 1978
Sherman, Louis A. 1 1980
Shibata, Kazuo 1 1975-
Shibata, Kazuo 1 1976
Shibata, Kazuo 1 1979
Shibata, Kazuo 1 1982
Shibata, Kazuo 1 1983
Siefermann, Dorothea 1 Scandinavia 74 Correspondence
Siminovitch, D. 2 Letters 1945-
Singer, Maxine 1 1987
Sinsheimer, Robert L. 1 1978
Sironval, C. 1 1983
Sironval, C. 1 1984
Skotnicki, T. J. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Slichter, Charles P. 1 1975-
Smith, Celia M. 1 1985
Smith, Emil L. 1 1973-74
Smith, James H. C. 2 1935-1950
Smith, James H. C. 2 1951-60
Snyder, Richard L. 1 1973-74
Somers, G. Fred 2 Letters 1945-
Song, Pill-Soon 1 1976
Speel, H. C. 2 Paint Letters 1941-49
Sperry, Helen A. 1 1983
Spikes, John D. 2 1951-60
Spoehr, H. A. 2 1935-1950
Statham, Louis 2 Letters 1945-
Stauffer, J. F. 2 Letters 1945-
Stieber, Michael T. 1 1985
Stifham, Mark A. 1 1980
Stout, Ernest R. 1 1973-74
Strasser, Reto 1 1975-
Stumpf, P. K. 1 1978
Sundqvist, Christer 1 1983
Sundqvist, Christer 1 1984
Tai, Willian 1978-79 (Tang corresp.)